DAVID WAGENHURST

wagenhurstd@gmail.com Tel: (972) 415-8763

GitHub: https://github.com/dwagenhurst

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-wagenhurst/

Dallas, TX

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a data scientist with nearly 5 years of experience working in the financial industry in both accounting and operations. I understand the importance of finance to both businesses and individuals and want to utilize my skillset for the betterment of others.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS_

Commercial Financial Services professional with a BS Mathematics and concentration in Probability & Data Analytics. Skilled in large data analysis and configuration, corporate trust transactions, analysis, and property accounting

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

Data Science Fellow

March 2022 – June 2022

- 500+ hour Data Science Immersive with a focus on true-to-life applications of data science and its principles.
- Experience includes data acquisition, cleaning, preprocessing, predictive modeling, constructing visualizations, and project presentation.
- Individual and group projects covering a variety of topics and techniques including; classification utilizing NLP, modeling housing prices, studying effects of oil refineries on health in Texas, and modeling effects of weather on marathon times.

Greystar

Property Accountant

March 2021 - March 2022

- Responsible for full-cycle G/L accounting and reporting for seven large multi-family portfolios
- Maintain and coordinate accounting control procedures by analyzing revenue and expenditure trends and recommending appropriate budget levels to ensure expenditure control
- Analyze and review accounting and financial resources for property acquisitions, dispositions, and closings and budgets and expenditures for local, state, federal, private funding, contracts, grants, and other corporate financial and accounting transactions
- Compile and analyze financial information in preparation for entry into various financial statements and accounting reports; make journal entries for recording in the general ledger by checking calculations, reviewing basis for figures, and balancing and reconciling figures
- Review budget, revenue, expense, payroll entries, invoices, and other documents; research and resolve discrepancies as necessary
- Perform bank reconciliations and wire transfers for deposit, make mortgage payments and distributions

Bank of America

Sr. Operations Analyst

October 2017 - March 2021

- Executed Private Bank custody services for over 30,200 individual securities within the Corporate Actions and Class Actions unit for over 100k monthly transactions
- Processed and reconciled corporate actions including cash & stock mergers, spin-offs, rights distributions, liquidations, stock dividends, partial defeasances, reverse splits, and stock exchanges valued at over \$10 million

• Configured data for analysis of account tax lot structure and cost basis transactions.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

August 2013 - May 2017

- Bachelor of Science in Mathematics
 - o Mathematical Sciences, Specialization in Statistics, Probability & Data Analysis
- Business Certificate

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- Python, pandas, sklearn, seaborn, selenium
- GitHub
- PostgreSQL querying
- Microsoft Excel functions: Macros, VLOOKUPs, developing conditional formulas, and pivot tables